Register of the Commission for Relief in Belgium Records, 1914-1930
Hoover Institution Archives
- WASHINGTON OFFICE FILES, 1917-1919.
  - Intra-agency correspondence. Correspondence between the Washington Office and other offices of the Commission for Relief in Belgium, 1917-1919
    - London Office, 1917-1919
      - Assistant Director (Lewis Richards)
        - 1918 (Folder 5)
      - Secretary (Herbert Owen), 1917-1918 (Folder 6)
      - Hill, Roland F., 1918 (Folder 7)
      - Shaler, Millard K., 1917-1918 (Folder 8)
      - Smith, Robinson, 1917-1918 (Folder 9)
      - Accountants Department, 1917-1918 (Folder 10)
      - Clothing Department, 1917 (Folder 11)
      - Shipping Department, 1918. Includes shipping reports received from London (Folder 12)
      - Statistics Department (George I. Gay), 1917-1919. Includes statistical reports received from London (Box 450, Folder 1)
    - Rotterdam Office (Walter Lyman Brown). Includes reports of ship arrivals in Rotterdam
      - 1917 (Folder 2)
      - 1918
        - January-June (Folder 3)
        - July-December (Folder 4)
    - Brussels Office, 1918-1919 (Folder 5)
    - Paris Office (Louis Chevrillon), 1917-1918 (Folder 6)
    - New York Office, 1917-1919
      - General, 1917-1919 (Folder 7)
      - Director (William L. Honnold)
        - 1917 (Folder 8)
        - 1918
          - January-February (Folder 9)
          - March-April (Folder 10)
          - May-June (Folder 11)
          - July-August (Box 451, Folder 1)
          - September-November (Folder 2)
      - Assistant Director (Prentiss N. Gray). Note: Gray was transferred from the New York Office to the Washington Office in 1918
        - 1917
          - July-October (Folder 3)
          - November-December (Folder 4)
        - 1918 (Folder 5)
      - Secretary (James A. Healy)
        - 1917 (Folder 6)
        - 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
      - Treasurer and Assistant Treasurers (Alexander J. Hemphill, Edward J. Williams, John S. Bradley)
        - 1917 (Folder 8)
        - 1918
          - January-June (Folder 9)
          - July-August (Folder 10)
          - September-December (Folder 11)
        - 1919 (Folder 12)
      - Cashier (George J. Garrity). Includes financial statements received from New York (Box 452)
        - 1917 (Folder 1)
        - 1918
          - January-May (Folder 2)
          - June-August (Folder 3)
          - September-December (Folder 4)
      - Accounting Department (T. J. Lewis), 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
      - Clothing Department (Milton M. Brown, Robert Arrowsmith, John S. Lawrence, Textile Alliance)
        - 1918
          - January-October (Folder 6)
          - November-December (Folder 7)
        - 1919 (Folder 8)
      - Lace Department (Thomas E. Dawber), 1918 (Folder 9)
      - Purchasing Department (Thomas E. Dawber), 1917-1918 (Folder 10)
      - Statistical Department (John S. Bradley). Includes shipping reports received from New York
        - 1918
          - February-April (Folder 11)
          - May-June (Folder 12)
          - July-August (Box 453, Folder 1)
          - September-October (Folder 2)
          - November-December (Folder 3)
        - 1919 (Folder 4)
      - Transportation Department (H. C. Davis)
        - 1917 (Folder 5)
        - 1918
          - January-May (Folder 6)
          - June-September (Folder 7)
          - October-December (Folder 8)
    - California Committee (Henry K. Norton, Sara D. Harker), 1917-1919 (Folder 9)
    - Chicago Committee (William J. Chalmers), 1917-1919 (Folder 10)
    - Pennsylvania Committee (Mrs. Bayard Henry, Mary Archer), 1918-1919 (Folder 11)
    - Tennessee Committee (Della Dortch), 1918 (Folder 12)
    - Washington (D.C.) Committee (Elena E. Rice), 1918 (Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous local committees, 1918 (Folder 14)
  - General correspondence, 1917-1919 (Box 454)
    - General, 1917-1919
      - A-F (Folder 1)
      - G-L (Folder 2)
      - M-R (Folder 3)
      - S-W (Folder 4)
    - A. Johnson and Company (G. Ekstrom), 1918 (Folder 5)
    - Albert I, King of the Belgians, 1917 (Folder 6)
    - American Committee for Armenian and Syrian Relief, 1918-1919. Includes related correspondence with the American Committee for Relief in the Near East (Folder 7)
    - American National Red Cross, 1918 (Folder 8)
    - American Security and Trust Company, 1918 (Folder 9)
    - Angell, Frank, 1918 (Folder 10)
    - Armour and Company, 1917 (Folder 11)
    - Arrowsmith, Robert, 1917-1919. See also Intra-agency correspondence/New York Office/Clothing Department (Folder 12)
    - Belgian Bureau (New York, N.Y.), 1918 (Folder 13)
    - Belgian Official Information Service (Washington, D.C.), 1918 (Folder 14)
    - Belgium. Armée, 1917-1918 (Folder 15)
    - Belgium. Consulat (Ottawa, Ont.), 1918 (Folder 16)
    - Belgium. Consulat Général (New York, N.Y.) (Pierre Mali), 1917-1918 (Folder 17)
    - Belgium. Légation (U.S.) (Baron E. de Cartier)
      - 1917 (Folder 18)
      - 1918
        - January-June (Folder 19)
        - July-December (Box 455, Folder 1)
    - Belgium. Ministère des Chemins de Fer, Marine Postes et Télégraphes (Paul Segers, A. Bultinck), 1917-1918 (Folder 2)
    - Belgium. Ministère des Finances, 1917 (Folder 3)
    - Bertron, S. Reading, 1917 (Folder 4)
    - Brinton, Willard C., 1918 (Folder 5)
    - Brown, Milton M., 1917-1918. See also Intra-agency correspondence/New York Office/Clothing Department (Folder 6)
    - Carton de Wiart, M. E., 1918 (Folder 7)
    - Comité d'Alimentation du Nord de la France, 1918 (Folder 8)
    - Comité National de Secours et d'Alimentation (Emile Francqui), 1917-1918 (Folder 9)
    - De Ropp, Alfred, 1918 (Folder 10)
    - Drake, Francis, 1917 (Folder 11)
    - Engelbracht, Charles A., 1918 (Folder 12)
    - Fallows, Edward H., 1917 (Folder 13)
    - Freeman and Westerhoff (Law firm), 1918 (Folder 14)
    - Gade, Helen R., 1918 (Folder 15)
    - Gans Steamship Line, 1918 (Folder 16)
    - George H. McFadden and Brother (Cotton brokerage), 1918 (Folder 17)
    - Great Britain. Embassy (U.S.) (Lord Eustace Percy), 1917-1918 (Folder 18)
    - Great Britain. Ministry of Food (W. A. M. Goode), 1917-1918 (Folder 19)
    - Great Britain. Ministry of Shipping, 1918 (Folder 20)
    - Gregory, Warren, 1918 (Folder 21)
    - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1918 (Folder 22)
    - Hall, William Chapman, 1918 (Folder 23)
    - Haut Commissariat de la République Française aux Etats-Unis (Emile Level, Edouard de Billy, André Tardieu), 1917-1919 (Folder 24)
    - Hill, Curtis, 1918 (Folder 25)
    - Holland America Line, 1918 (Folder 26)
    - Joint Distribution Committee of the American Funds for Jewish War Sufferers, 1918 (Folder 27)
    - Mercier, D. J., Cardinal, 1917-1919 (Folder 28)
    - Merrell-Soule Company, 1917 (Folder 29)
    - Millard, Everett L., 1919 (Folder 30)
    - Morgenthau, Henry, 1917 (Folder 31)
    - National Committee for Relief in Belgium, 1917 (Folder 32)
    - Nederlandsch-Belgisch Hoofdcomité voor Propaganda ter Huisvesting van Belgische Kinderen in Nederland (Comtesse M. de Liedekerke), 1918 (Folder 33)
    - Nederlandsche Gist- en Spiritusfabriek (F. E. Vlielander Hein), 1918 (Folder 34)
    - Netherlands. Gezantschap (U.S.), 1917-1918 (Folder 35)
    - Norton, Lilly and Company, 1918 (Box 456, Folder 1)
    - Norway. Special Mission to the United States (Johan Baumann), 1917 (Folder 2)
    - Pro Belgica, 1918 (Folder 3)
    - Sherman, Roger, 1918 (Folder 4)
    - Sweden. Legation (U.S.), 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
    - Switzerland. Légation (U.S.), 1917-1918 (Folder 6)
    - Thomas Harling and Son (Steamship agency), 1918 (Folder 7)
    - United States. Dept. of Commerce, 1917-1918 (Folder 8)
    - United States. Dept. of State (William Phillips)
      - 1917 (Folder 9)
      - 1918
        - January-April (Folder 10)
        - May-October (Folder 11)
        - November-December (Folder 12)
      - 1919 (Folder 13)
    - United States. Dept. of the Treasury (William G. McAdoo, Robert C. Leffingwell, Albert Rathbone)
      - 1917 (Folder 14)
      - 1918
        - January-September (Folder 15)
        - October-December (Folder 16)
      - 1919 (Folder 17)
    - United States. Food Administration (New York Office) Julius H. Barnes, Wallace H. Foster, Arthur Ryan, F. G. Crowell)
      - 1918
        - April-August (Folder 18)
        - September (Box 457, Folder 1)
        - October (Folder 2)
        - November (Folder 3)
        - December
          - 1-15 (Folder 4)
          - 16-31 (Folder 5)
      - 1919 (Folder 6)
    - United States. Food Administration (offices other than New York), 1918 (Folder 7)
    - United States. Fuel Administration, 1917-1918 (Folder 8)
    - United States. Navy Dept., 1917-1918 (Folder 9)
    - United States. Shipping Board. Includes related correspondence the Shipping Control Committee
      - 1917 (Folder 10)
      - 1918
        - January-August (Folder 11)
        - September-October (Folder 12)
        - November-December (Folder 13)
    - United States. War Dept., 1918 (Box 458, Folder 1)
    - United States. War Industries Board, 1918-1919 (Folder 2)
    - United States. War Trade Board (Frank C. Munson, John Beaver White), 1918 (Folder 3)
    - Wheat Export Company, 1918 (Folder 4)
    - Willcox, Peck and Hughes (Insurance brokerage), 1918 (Folder 5)
    - Woman's Magazine, 1918 (Folder 6)
  - Personnel records. Lists, letters from applicants, and miscellany, 1917-1918 (Folder 7)
  - Publicity materials. Circulars and drafts for circulars, 1917-1918 (Folder 8)
  - Clothing campaign records. Correspondence, memoranda and press releases, 1917-1918. See also Intra-agency correspondence/New York Office/Clothing Department (Folder 9)
  - Purchasing records, 1918
    - General. Correspondence, memoranda and priority certificates (Folder 10)
    - Purchasing approvals
      - United States. Food Administration. Division of Coordination of Purchase (Folder 11)
      - United States. War Industries Board (Folder 12)
      - United States. Grain Corporation (Folder 13)
  - Shipping records, 1917-1918
    - Correspondence, 1917 (Folder 14)
    - Charts, 1918 (Box 459, Folder 1)
    - Reports, 1918
      - Particulars regarding steamers (Folder 2)
      - Sailings (Folder 3)
  - Subject file, 1917-1918
    - American-Belgian Foundation. Report, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Assistance Discrète (Organization). Reports, 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
    - Brazilian shipping. Correspondence and memoranda, 1917 (Folder 6)
    - Comptoir National pour la Reprise de l'Activité Economique en Belgique. Press release, n.d. (Folder 7)
    - Convoys. Notes, n.d. (Folder 8)
    - Dutch shipping. Correspondence and memoranda, 1917-1918 (Folder 9)
    - Humbert, Pierre. Correspondence, 1917 (Folder 10)
    - Insurance. Correspondence and memoranda, 1917-1918 (Folder 11)
    - Mail procedures. Memorandum, n.d. (Folder 12)
    - Norwegian shipping. Correspondence and memoranda, 1917. See also General correspondence/Norway. Special Mission to the United States (Folder 13)
    - Regained territory (Belgium and France). Report and memoranda, 1918 (Folder 14)
    - Shipping containers. Report and statistics, 1917-1918 (Folder 15)
    - Shipping rates. Statistics, n.d. (Folder 16)
    - Vessels lost. Lists, 1918 (Folder 17)
  - Maps, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Statistics, Miscellaneous, 1918-1919 (Folder 19)
  - Miscellany. Lists, notes, clippings and hearing transcript, 1917-1918 (Folder 20)
- AMERICAN COMMITTEE FILE, 1911-1917
  - Bulletins (Box 460, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence. Includes invoices, printed matter, receipts, reports, and telegrams enclosed with letters addressed to Herbert Hoover
    - 1914
      - July (Folder 2)
      - August (Folder 3)
      - September (Folder 4)
      - October (Folder 5)
      - November (Folder 6)
      - December (Folder 7)
    - 1915-1916 (Folder 8)
  - Reports
    - 1911. Includes report on the speeches given by R. Newton Crane, Harry Lawson, Whitelaw Reid, J. Morgan Richards, Frederick C. Van Duzer and others at the Thanksgiving Day Banquet (Folder 9)
    - 1914 (Folder 10)
    - 1914-1915 (Folder 11)
  - Women's Division file
    - Correspondence. Includes letters written by Lou Henry Hoover (Folder 12)
    - Membership list (Folder 13)
    - Printed matter (Folder 14)
    - Report of the Chairman, Lou Henry Hoover, (also of the Resident American Women's Relief Committee of London) (Folder 15)
    - Miscellany (Folder 16)
- GREATER NEW YORK COMMITTEE FILES, 1916-1917
  - Internal correspondence. Correspondence with the national Commission for Relief in Belgium (Box 461)
    - 1916
      - January
        - 5-22 (Folder 1)
        - 24-31 (Folder 2)
      - February
        - 1-9 (Folder 3)
        - 10-29 (Folder 4)
      - March (Folder 5)
      - April (Folder 6)
      - May (Folder 7)
      - June-December (Folder 8)
    - 1917 (Folder 9)
  - General correspondence
    - 1916
      - General
        - A (Folder 10)
        - B-Ba (Folder 11)
        - Be-Bi (Folder 12)
        - Bl-Bre (Box 462, Folder 1)
        - Bri-By (Folder 2)
        - C-Cha (Folder 3)
        - Che-Cl (Folder 4)
        - Co-Coo (Folder 5)
        - Cor-Cu (Folder 6)
        - D-Dek (Folder 7)
        - Del-Di (Folder 8)
        - Do-Dy (Folder 9)
        - E (Folder 10)
        - F-Fi (Folder 11)
        - Fl-Fu (Folder 12)
        - G-Goo (Box 463, Folder 1)
        - Gor-Gu (Folder 2)
        - H-Har (Folder 3)
        - Has-He (Folder 4)
        - Hi-Hoo (Folder 5)
        - Hop-Hu (Folder 6)
        - I-J (Folder 7)
        - K (Folder 8)
        - L-Le (Folder 9)
        - Li-Ly (Folder 10)
        - M-Mac (Folder 11)
        - Mad-May (Folder 12)
        - Me-Mol (Box 464, Folder 1)
        - Mon-My (Folder 2)
        - N-O (Folder 3)
        - P-Pec (Folder 4)
        - Peg-Ph (Folder 5)
        - Pi-Pu (Folder 6)
        - Q-Ri (Folder 7)
        - Ro-Ry (Folder 8)
        - S-Se (Folder 9)
        - Sh-Sl (Folder 10)
        - Sm-Sn (Folder 11)
        - So-Sy (Folder 12)
        - T-Th (Box 465, Folder 1)
        - Ti-Ty (Folder 2)
        - U-V (Folder 3)
        - W-Wa (Folder 4)
        - We-Wh (Folder 5)
        - Wi-Wy (Folder 6)
        - Y-Z (Folder 7)
      - Brooklyn residents
        - A-F (Folder 8)
        - G-L (Folder 9)
        - M-W (Folder 10)
      - New Jersey residents
        - A-E (Folder 11)
        - F-L (Folder 12)
        - M-R (Box 466, Folder 1)
        - S-W (Folder 2)
    - 1917 (Folder 3)
  - Publicity materials. Leaflets, newspaper advertisements, and drafts of advertisements, 1916 (Folder 4)
  - Subject file, 1915-1916
    - Clothing campaign. Correspondence, lists and notes, 1915-1916 (Folder 5)
    - Committee membership. Correspondence regarding invitations to join committee, 1916 (Folder 6)
    - Donations, Miscellaneous. Notations of individual contributions, 1916 (Folder 7-8)
    - Thé Dansant (fundraising event in New York City, 1916)
      - General. Memoranda, lists, invitations, and publicity material, 1916 (Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1916
        - January (Folder 10)
        - February-March (Folder 11)
  - Miscellany. Lists, memoranda, notes and financial records, 1916-1917 (Folder 12)
- INDIANA COMMITTEE FILES, 1915-1916
  - Internal correspondence. Correspondence with the national Commission for Relief in Belgium (Box 467)
    - 1915
      - March-June (Folder 1)
      - July-December (Folder 2)
    - 1916 (Folder 3)
  - General correspondence
    - 1915
      - March-May (Folder 4)
      - June
        - 1-15 (Folder 5)
        - 16-30 (Folder 6)
      - July
        - 1-15 (Folder 7)
        - 16-31 (Folder 8)
      - August-September (Folder 9)
      - October-December (Folder 10)
    - 1916 (Folder 11)
  - Financial records. Vouchers, canceled checks, and financial statements
    - 1915 (Box 468, Folder 1)
    - 1916 (Folder 2)
  - Miscellany. Memoranda, notes and lists, 1915 (Folder 3)
- PENNSYLVANIA COMMITTEE FILES, 1915-1917
  - Organizational file. Materials relating to the establishment of the committee and to changes in membership of the state and local committees, 1915-1917 (Box 469)
    - General. Memoranda, press releases, and membership lists, 1915-1916 (Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - 1915
        - April (Folder 2)
        - May-July (Folder 3)
        - August-December (Folder 4)
      - 1916-1917 (Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1915 (Folder 6)
  - Internal correspondence. Correspondence with the national Commission for Relief in Belgium
    - 1915
      - March-May (Folder 7)
      - June-December (Folder 8)
    - 1916 (Box 470)
      - January-March (Folder 1)
      - April-December (Folder 2)
    - 1917 (Folder 3)
  - General correspondence
    - 1915
      - February-April (Folder 4)
      - May-December (Folder 5)
    - 1916
      - January-November (Folder 6)
      - December
        - 1-11 (Folder 7)
        - 12-30 (Folder 8)
    - 1917
      - January-April (Folder 9)
      - May-October (Folder 10)
  - Donations file. Letters of acknowledgement, other correspondence, lists of contributors, statistics, and notations of individual contributions, 1915-1917 (Box 471)
    - Cash donations
      - 1915
        - February-June (Folder 1)
        - July-December (Folder 2)
      - 1916
        - January-April (Folder 3)
        - May-December (Folder 4)
      - 1917
        - January-February (Folder 5)
        - March-July (Folder 6)
      - Undated (Folder 7)
    - Donations in kind, 1915-1917 (Folder 8)
    - Salt donation (International Salt Company), 1915 (Folder 9)
  - Financial records, 1915-1917
    - Correspondence
      - 1915 (Folder 10)
      - 1916 (Folder 11)
      - 1917 (Folder 12)
    - Expense statements, 1915-1917 (Box 472, Folder 1)
    - Bank book, 1915-1917 (Folder 2)
    - Canceled checks
      - 1915 (Folder 3)
      - 1916 (Folder 4)
    - Check stubs, 1915 (Folder 5)
    - Miscellany. Bills, receipts and notes, 1915-1917 (Folder 6-7)
  - Publicity materials. Press releases, leaflets, and drafts of press releases, 1915-1917 (Folder 8)
  - Shipping records, 1915-1917
    - General correspondence, 1915-1917 (Folder 9)
    - Curtis Publishing Company correspondence, 1915-1917 (Folder 10)
  - Miscellany. Memoranda, notes and lists, 1915-1917 (Folder 11)
  - Printed matter. Clippings, and publicity materials of other relief organizations, 1914-1915 (Folder 12)
  - Subject file, 1915-1917 (Box 473)
    - Allied Bazaar (fundraising event in New York City, 1916)
      - General. Publicity materials, bulletins, memoranda, notes and lists of contributors, 1916 (Folder 1)
      - Internal correspondence (with the national Commission for Relief in Belgium), 1916 (Folder 2)
      - General correspondence, 1916 (Folder 3)
    - Audiovisual material. Material regarding use of motion picture film, slides and stereopticons in conjunction with fundraising
      - Internal correspondence (with the national Commission for Relief in Belgium), 1915-1917 (Folder 4)
      - General correspondence, 1915-1917 (Folder 5)
    - Belgian Self-Sacrifice Day (fundraising drive, 1916). Lists of contributors and contributions, notes, and clipping, 1916-1917 (Folder 6)
    - Belgian Tag Day (fundraising drive, 1916). Correspondence and notes, 1916 (Folder 7)
    - Clothing campaign (collection drive). Correspondence and memoranda, 1915-1916 (Folder 8)
    - Cookbook sales. Material regarding publication and sale of a Belgian relief cookbook to raise funds
      - General. Publicity material, memoranda, notes and financial records, 1915-1917 (Folder 9)
      - Endorsement solicitations. Correspondence and notes, 1915 (Folder 10)
      - Correspondence (Box 474)
        - 1915 (Folder 1)
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 2)
    - Emergency Aid Committee (Philadelphia). Correspondence regarding, 1915-1916 (Folder 3)
    - Food box sales (fundraising drive). Correspondence and publicity material, 1915 (Folder 4)
    - Northumberland County (Pa.) campaign. Correspondence and memoranda, 1916-1917 (Folder 5)
    - Pledge card appeal (fundraising drive). Correspondence, notes and publicity material, 1916 (Folder 6)
    - Representative in Belgium. Correspondence regarding recruitment of a field worker to be sent to Belgium, 1915-1916 (Folder 7)
    - Theatrical productions (as proposed fundraising events). Correspondence, 1915 (Folder 8)
  - Belgian Children's Fund records. Correspondence, notes and lists of contributors, 1917
    - March-April (Folder 9)
    - May-June (Folder 10)
  - Woman's Section records. Correspondence, memoranda and lists
    - 1915 (Folder 11)
    - 1916 (Folder 12)
    - 1917 (Folder 13)
- STANFORD-PALO ALTO BELGIAN RELIEF COMMITTEE FILES, 1914-1919
  - History. Chronology, notes, and drafts for a history of the organization, n.d. (Box 475, Folder 1)
  - Journal of organization activities, 1915-1918 (Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1914-1918 (Folder 3)
  - Membership list, 1918 (Folder 4)
  - Internal correspondence. Correspondence with the California Committee for Relief in Belgium and France and with the national Commission for Relief in Belgium
    - 1915 (Folder 5)
    - 1916 (Folder 6)
    - 1917 (Folder 7)
    - 1918 (Folder 8)
    - 1919 (Folder 9)
  - General correspondence
    - 1914
      - A-M (Folder 10)
      - N-Y (Folder 11)
    - 1915
      - A (Folder 12)
      - B (Folder 13)
      - C-G (Folder 14)
      - H-J (Folder 15)
      - K-L (Folder 16)
      - M (Box 476, Folder 1)
      - N-P (Folder 2)
      - R-T (Folder 3)
      - V-Y (Folder 4)
    - 1916
      - A-C (Folder 5)
      - D (Folder 6)
      - E-H (Folder 7)
      - I-L (Folder 8)
      - M-R (Folder 9)
      - S-Y (Folder 10)
    - 1917 (Box 477)
      - A-E (Folder 1)
      - F-J (Folder 2)
      - K-M (Folder 3)
      - N-W (Folder 4)
    - 1918
      - A-D (Folder 5)
      - E-L (Folder 6)
      - M-R (Folder 7)
      - S-W (Folder 8)
    - 1919 (Folder 9)
  - Financial records. Reports, lists of contributions and contributors, letters, and canceled checks, 1914-1919
    - General
      - 1914 (Folder 10)
      - 1915 (Box 478, Folder 1)
      - 1916 (Folder 2)
      - 1917 (Folder 3)
      - 1918 (Folder 4)
      - 1919 (Folder 5)
    - Account books, 1915-1919 (Folder 6)
    - Receipt books
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 7)
      - 1916-1917 (Folder 8)
      - 1917-1919 (Folder 9)
  - Publicity materials. Circulars, leaflets, pamphlets, stickers, receipt cards, and gift cards. Includes some material issued by the national Commission for Relief in Belgium and distributed by the Stanford-Palo Alto Belgian Relief Committee
    - 1914-1915 (Folder 10)
    - 1916 (Folder 11)
    - 1917 (Folder 12)
    - 1918-1919 (Box 479, Folder 1)
  - Subject file, 1914-1919
    - Belgian Market (benefit sale in Palo Alto, 1918). Programs, memoranda, reports, and promotional material, 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Berkeley Committee play script for Belgian relief, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - California Committee for Relief in Belgium and France
      - List of chairmen of local branches, 1919 (Folder 4)
      - Reports
        - 1916 (Folder 5)
        - 1917 (Folder 6)
        - 1918 (Folder 7)
        - 1919 (Folder 8)
      - Circulars
        - 1914-1916 (Folder 9)
        - 1917 (Folder 10)
        - 1918 (Folder 11)
        - 1919 (Folder 12)
      - Publicity materials. Pamphlets, leaflets, and cards, 1915-1919 (Folder 13)
    - Conference, Call for, Palo Alto, 1918. Correspondence and circulars, 1918 (Box 480, Folder 1)
    - Guilbert (Yvette) benefit concert, Stanford University, 1918. Correspondence, programs and promotional material, 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Clippings and other collected printed matter regarding Belgian relief
      - 1914-1915 (Folder 3)
      - 1916 (Folder 4)
      - 1917 (Folder 5)
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
      - Undated (Folder 7)
    - Printing blocks and rubber stamps (Folder 8-9)
- STANFORD COMMITTEE FOR FRENCH RELIEF FILES, 1919-1920